<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>moo&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://kammhoff.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on moo&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kammhoff.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail &#43; Custom Domain</title>
      <link>https://kammhoff.com/gmaildomain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kammhoff.com/gmaildomain/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gmail-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Gmail + Custom Domain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you could go and pay for Google Apps, but that&amp;rsquo;s about 5€ a month for using a custom email address, why do this if you can literally get the same result for free?
So here we go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-purchase-the-domain&#34;&gt;Step 1: Purchase the Domain!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just head over to the service of your choice (in my case namecheap.com) and purchase the domain of your choice. Since this is my first time doing this, I went with kammhoff.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-receiving-mail&#34;&gt;Step 2: Receiving Mail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Receiving mail is quite simple, just head into your domain settings and add email forwarding for your desired email, in this case blog@kammhoff.com
&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;image of settings&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-sending-mail&#34;&gt;Step 3: Sending Mail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple services providing a SMTP relay, usually used for newsletters and similar. They often offer free tiers up to a couple thousand emails a day/month, so there won&amp;rsquo;t be any additional cost for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very popular choice is &lt;a href=&#34;mailgun.com&#34;&gt;mailgun.com&lt;/a&gt;. Due to its popularity many people use it for spamming though, which puts some of the IPs on blacklists. This results in your mail possibly getting filtered or not sent, something which you obviously want to avoid. In fact, according to this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bugmuncher.com/blog/moving-away-from-mandrill/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, which is referencing a statistic from &lt;a href=&#34;inboxtrail.com&#34;&gt;inboxtrail&lt;/a&gt;, only 61.25% of mail sent through mailgun is delivered.
This is quite a terrible stat, so I went on to look for a different solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first alternative I found was &lt;a href=&#34;zoho.com&#34;&gt;zoho&lt;/a&gt;. But it just felt like it was too much, it was a full mail client, CRM, and so much more. I was perfectly happy with Gmail, which ended up making me consider &lt;a href=&#34;sparkpost.com&#34;&gt;sparkpost.com&lt;/a&gt;.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything wrong with it, so I decided to go for it and set up my free account.
Being in the free tier I am able to send 10,000 emails/DAY, a number I will never reach with my intended purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During account creation you will be asked to add a domain. Just enter the previously purchased domain, and continue.
Afterwards you need to verify ownership of the domain, by either adding a SPF/DKIM record to your DNS or verifying through email. I ended up doing all of these things. Just to be sure, you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the email verification method, add one of the displayed addresses to the email forwarding in your domain settings. Send the mail, click the link, done! If you want to, you can delete the forwarding address after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add the DNS records just head over to your domain settings, and add the records displayed on sparkposts verification site.
&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;image of verification process&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might take a few minutes to complete, but we can use this time to setup the gmail part of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head over to your gmail account, go to Settings-&amp;gt;Accounts and Import.
Click on &amp;lsquo;Add another email address&amp;rsquo; on the &amp;lsquo;Send mail as&amp;rsquo; section.
Go back to the sparkpost dashboard, and click on &amp;lsquo;Setup SMTP Relay&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;image of smtp relay location&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now enter the sparkpost information into the gmail form, accept and confirm the received email. You should probably also write down the password somewhere.
&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;imageS of gmail form&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After adding the email address in your Gmail settings, you can go ahead and tick &amp;lsquo;Reply from the same address the message was sent to&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;image of gmail settings&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the only thing left is waiting for the DNS records to update, and the sparkposts domain verification to succeed! Once that is done, you will be able to use gmail for receiving/sending mail through your custom email address!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;image of sending mail through new address&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My descend into /r/MechanicalKeyboards - or: The WhiteFox</title>
      <link>https://kammhoff.com/blog/my-descend-into-/r/mechanicalkeyboards---or-the-whitefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kammhoff.com/blog/my-descend-into-/r/mechanicalkeyboards---or-the-whitefox/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;backstory&#34;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using mechanical keyboards since about 2014, when I first bought a &amp;lsquo;gaming&amp;rsquo; keyboard, the QPAD MK-80 with Cherry MX Brown switches.&lt;br /&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s been through a lot, been cleaned numerous amount of times, and is still performing as new.&lt;br /&gt;
So why go and buy a custom keyboard? Well, the answer is quite simple: I got sick and tired of the &amp;lsquo;gaming&amp;rsquo; look of things.&lt;br /&gt;
Red LEDs, branding, silly symbols. I just got sick of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my journey into madness began..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;qpad image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-long-process-a-timeline&#34;&gt;The (long) process &amp;ndash; A Timeline&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2015 I first watched Rhinofeed&amp;rsquo;s POK3R video, after seeing it shared by @nikftw on twitter.
It looked nice and all, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like it was a major upgrade from what I was already using, and had just bought about 10 months prior.
So back into hibernation mode I went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August 2015 I quit my WoW career, and thus my life as a &amp;lsquo;gamer&amp;rsquo;. I was beginning to move forward. Ever since, I have slowly been phasing out my gaming branded gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 31st of December 2015, fittingly, ended up being the big day. After moving back to the UK @nikftw posted a picture of his new setup. I rememberd him posting about the POK3R back then, and some of his following tweets about keycaps and his very own POKER II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nikftw/status/682352045509193728?lang=de&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/nikftw/status/682352045509193728?lang=de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been visiting /r/battlestations for quite a while at this point, so I really liked his clean setup. But something stood out to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I really liked his keyboard.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time I still had to get rid of the last remaining part of my gaming equipment:&lt;br /&gt;
My oversized, red backlit QPAD MK-80.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;image of tweet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I was, getting sucked into /r/MechanicalKeyboards.&lt;br /&gt;
I spent multiple days just browsing through this new world. The variety of layouts, keycaps, cables, everything.&lt;br /&gt;
While going through the posts I found a picture of matt3o&amp;rsquo;s Granite keycap set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fell in love.&lt;br /&gt;
I loved the look of these keycaps, the clean and simple look. The finish. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop looking for more Granite pictures.&lt;br /&gt;
I started looking into ways of me acquiring them. I discovered /r/mechmarket, but being from europe I quickly realized that chances of me being able to buy a second hand set of Granite keycaps was about zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just a few weeks later it happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;january-12th-2016&#34;&gt;January 12th, 2016&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt3o&amp;rsquo;s Granite Keycap set went on sale on massdrop.com. It was the fourth round, supposedly the final one.&lt;br /&gt;
Of course I had to get in on this, there was no way I was going to miss out on this! Who could have thought, that SignaturePlastics was just going to cash in on the massive success of the keycaps? Right..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was more. In the massdrop promo pictures of the set, there was this keyboard.&lt;br /&gt;
It was &lt;strong&gt;simple&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
It was &lt;strong&gt;beautiful&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
It was &lt;strong&gt;65%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
It had the &lt;strong&gt;HHKB layout&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
It was &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt; I wanted from a keyboard, and more.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I had to have it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to reddit I go, inquiring about the source of this picture.&lt;br /&gt;
Turns out it was matt3o&amp;rsquo;s WhiteFox, a drop that just ended ~2 weeks prior to the Granite drop! No wonder they fit so well together, both being created by matt3o&amp;rsquo;s himself.&lt;br /&gt;
The next round was scheduled for Q3 2016.&lt;br /&gt;
Being no stranger of waiting, I went for it. I bought all the required Granite keycaps, sat back, and started my watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Massdrop had the usual delays with the Granite keycaps, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less.&lt;br /&gt;
In May I received my package.&lt;br /&gt;
To check for any issues I quickly popped them onto my QPAD MK-80. Some of the keys very slightly angled, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much of an issue for me.&lt;br /&gt;
Being happy with the keycaps, they went back into storage. Because let&amp;rsquo;s be real, the keycaps were never meant for the QPAD. They had to remain pure, for the day of marriage between WhiteFox and Granite. Matt3o&amp;rsquo;s creations united.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;july-22nd-2016&#34;&gt;July 22nd, 2016&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;image of email&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happened, and it happened early!&lt;br /&gt;
There really wasn&amp;rsquo;t much to do here. I obviously joined the drop.&lt;br /&gt;
My choice was always clear, I had to have the matt3o&amp;rsquo;s TrueFox.&lt;br /&gt;
The switch choice was also clear, it had to be the Zealios 65g. All issues regarding key chatter were supposed to be cleared up after the first round of them, and they were the perfect compromise between my own Cherry MX Browns and the Ergo Clears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to wanting Zealios switches the assembled option wasn&amp;rsquo;t avilable. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have wanted to take it anyways.&lt;br /&gt;
So I had to choose between the DIY and base kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The base kit only contained the plate, PCB, case, feet, screws and stabilizers.&lt;br /&gt;
The DIY kit also contained a cable, keycaps, 70 white LEDs and 70 switches of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have bought all parts seperately, since I really didn&amp;rsquo;t need the keycaps. But it would not have been much cheaper, and I thought having the keycaps/cable as backup for a time, when I want to move the Granite keys to a different keyboards, was a nice option. Additionally I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay import taxes for multiple seperate orders.&lt;br /&gt;
So I went with the more expensive DIY option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expected shipping date was November 16th, 2016. I was aware of this probably getting delayed, but I was still hoping for a WhiteFox christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the very end of the drop the first issue came up. The stabilizer cutouts in the plates were wrong on almost all the plates. There would be a delay. Very much expected.&lt;br /&gt;
So I was very surprised, when on December 13th I received this email:&lt;br /&gt;
shipping email&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual the internation DHL tracking didn&amp;rsquo;t work, but after a few days the package already showed up on the national post tracking. On December 22nd, after paying ridiculous amounts of import taxes, I was able to truly call the WhiteFox mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrapped the package and put it under the christmas tree. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t felt this excited for christmas in many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-assembly&#34;&gt;The Assembly&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start talking about the actual keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After enduring all the social obligations that christmas comes with, I was finally able to assemble my WhiteFox, which I have been waiting for over 11 months at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This being my first build, I was quite slow when it came to the actual process of building the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched all of InputClubs WhiteFox assembly videos before even getting out my tools. During the actual process I just followed the steps showcased in the videos, the process turned out to be pretty straight forward after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encountered my first issue when it came to mounting the PCB on the switches. I bent quite a few pins, had to pop out quite a few switches and paid the usual blood sacrifice on the plate. But after some time the PCB fit unde the plate, and all the pins from the switches were poking out, ready to be soldered.&lt;br /&gt;
The soldering process itself actually turned out to be the easiest process of building a keyboard. Even tho I used a cheapo 15€ soldering iron, I had zero issues.&lt;br /&gt;
Afterwards came the LEDs, which I first didn&amp;rsquo;t even want to use. But well, I paid for them. Might aswell, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Push the LEDs into the switch, bent the pins, solder to PCB. Very straight forward, very easy. I didnt&amp;rsquo; have a cable cutter available, so I ended up just using my nail clipper to trim the LED pins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now came a moment of shock. I assumed that a one month delay would mean, that all plates were fixed and no longer affected by the cutout issues. Oh boy, was I wrong.&lt;br /&gt;
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even mount my stabilizers the intended way! I had to turn them upside down, and still only &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of them worked. The enter key is dampened by the wire rubbing against the switch housing. But oh well, I contacted massdrop about the issue and will see what the outcome of this stabilizer issue is going to be. I&amp;rsquo;m certainly not going to desolder all of these switches and LEDs, that&amp;rsquo;s sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put the PCB/plate combo into the case, and oh no! The dampening was too thick. Or, as I later realized, the PCB was mounted properly. Oh well, away you go dampening!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it was time to add some keycaps. I popped on the WhiteFox keycaps, did some quick tests, and put them back into their packaging.&lt;br /&gt;
whitefox with whitefox keycaps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time for the Granite keycaps to come out of storage.&lt;br /&gt;
Quickly unpacked and put on the keyboard, and I was very much in love at this point. It was everthing I wanted it to be. It was as beautiful ad the image I had seen almost one year before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;whitefox with whitefox keycaps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being happy with the physical result of the keyboard, I turned to the software side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I flashed a basic TrueFox-Blank layout from the InputClub configurator, to test all the switches.&lt;br /&gt;
Everything was fine, so I started to go deeper.
I quickly realized that the configurator itself was quite limited, and started looking for ways of compiling my own layouts.&lt;br /&gt;
The things I needed from this custom layout to do, are as follows:&lt;br /&gt;
- German umlaute without some weird alt keycode&lt;br /&gt;
- Macros&lt;br /&gt;
- Sequences (for boolean operators or similar)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kiibohd/controller&#34;&gt;KLL controller repo&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub, and was happy to find a quite detailed [documentation]&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kiibohd/controller/wiki/KLL)&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kiibohd/controller/wiki/KLL)&lt;/a&gt; for it.&lt;br /&gt;
So I went ahead and set up cygwin and all the required packages on my system, and started creating my own layout.&lt;br /&gt;
The process was very straight forward and easy to follow. You can find my results &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rammoo/dotfiles/tree/master/WhiteFox&#34;&gt;on my GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;inputclub layout editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I was, having my dream keyboard right in front me. My family right behind me, thinking I&amp;rsquo;ve gone completely crazy.&lt;br /&gt;
I went onto typeracer.com, hoping to get used to the new layout rather fast. Within a few races I started encountering issues. The keyboard seemed to be crashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;keyboard crashes youtube link&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reflashed the default TrueFox layout, but the issue kept existing. I checked all the soldering connections on the PCB, but they all seemed to be fine. After unplugging and replugging, the keyboard seemed to be working fine too.&lt;br /&gt;
Going through all the usual troubleshooting steps, I fired up my X220 laptop running Arch, and did some races on typeracer.com.&lt;br /&gt;
And it all worked fine! Back to Windows I go, and within a few minutes the keyboard crashes multiple times.&lt;br /&gt;
Being beyond confused at this point, I decided to try using the dampening foam to avoid any possible static being caused by the PCB being too close to the case bottom. And like a miracle, the issue stopped happening.&lt;br /&gt;
While there was absolutely no way of me ever desoldering all the switches and LEDs, I went ahead and just tried forcing the plate onto the foam. And it worked. But it looked bad. Like not flush bad. Like this is unacceptably bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I removed the foam, and looked for another solution. The foam is way too thin, to cut it to half the height. So I needed something else. I ended up just using a few layers of paper (around 1mm) and cutting out the holes for the electronics.&lt;br /&gt;
After reassembling everthing with the new 1mm paper layer I had a perfectly flush fit and was satisfied with the physical appearance. I haven&amp;rsquo;t encountered any issues while writing this blog, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just hope it is fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now here I am, owner of matt3o&amp;rsquo;s ultimate creation: The Granite TrueFox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;final image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-words&#34;&gt;Final Words&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve now been using the keyboard for a few days, and have been asking myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;was-it-worth-it&#34;&gt;Was it worth it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had many regrets between January last year and this day. Many of those were related to massdrop, delays and quality issues.&lt;br /&gt;
But at the end of the day, here I am, owner of the very product I only dared to dream of a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The typing experience is superb. There really isn&amp;rsquo;t anything else to say here. The enter key has some stabilizer issues, but I literally can&amp;rsquo;t notice it during regular typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design is beautiful. The CNC&amp;rsquo;d aluminum case is possibly the nicest thing I have ever had the honor of touching. It has a very heavy and quality feel to it, I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Granite keycaps are everything I could have hoped for. The DSA profile makes them great to use, the material feels lovely and there really isn&amp;rsquo;t anything left to say about the looks of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The layout is great, it only took me a couple of hours to get entirely used to it and being back to my usual wpm on typeracer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have to say, &lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, it was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the only thing left is enjoying this beauty.&lt;br /&gt;
Followed by probably buying a HHKB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kammhoff.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 06:42:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kammhoff.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi!&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m Niklas &amp;lsquo;rammo&amp;rsquo; Kammhoff, a 20 year old Software Engineering student at the University of Stuttgart.&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll be using this blog to talk about things that interest me, as well as day to day events in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes my personal projects, programming topics, movies, general technology and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kammhoff.com/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 06:42:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kammhoff.com/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog does not share personal information with third parties nor do we store any information about your visit to this blog other than to analyze and optimize your content and reading experience through the use of cookies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can turn off the use of cookies at anytime by changing your specific browser settings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We are not responsible for republished content from this blog on other blogs or websites without our permission.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This privacy policy is subject to change without notice and was last updated on&lt;br /&gt;
January, 06, 2017.&lt;br /&gt;
If you have any questions feel free to contact me directly here: niklas@kammhoff.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://kammhoff.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kammhoff.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing yet :(&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kammhoff.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kammhoff.com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog does not share personal information with third parties nor do we store any information about your visit to this blog other than to analyze and optimize your content and reading experience through the use of cookies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can turn off the use of cookies at anytime by changing your specific browser settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not responsible for republished content from this blog on other blogs or websites without our permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This privacy policy is subject to change without notice and was last updated on January, 06, 2017. If you have any questions feel free to contact me directly here: niklas@kammhoff.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>